[Music]
ldl bad cholesterol is bad but oxidized
ldl may be worse
what role might our diet play
increased fruit and vegetable
consumption has been reported to reduce
the risk of developing cardiovascular
disease heart attacks and strokes well
maybe it's in part because of all the
antioxidants in healthy plant foods
preventing the oxidation of ldl
cholesterol
and indeed the ldl oxidation resistance
was found to be greatest among those
eating more plant-based
so that would be in addition to the
decreased blood pressure and lower ldl
overall
in terms of beneficial effects but you
don't know if it's cause and effect
until you put it to the test
put people on a whole food plant-based
diet for just three weeks and
rates and extent of ldl oxidation drop
the effects of kale on ldl oxidation was
put to the test kale is a best of all
worlds food low in calories packed to
the hill with nutrition vitamins
minerals anti-inflammatory compounds
antioxidant phytonutrients you name it
no surprise then given its high
antioxidant capacity kale showed a
protective effect on the oxidation of
ldl even at low concentrations
but this was in vitro in a test tube
kale was also put to the test in mice
but what about
people
i did a video on this study on how kale
juice improves
coronary artery disease risk factors in
men with high cholesterol extraordinary
results a 20 drop in ldl among the
non-smokers
but they were drinking the equivalent of
about 10 cups of kale a day
still the the fact that they were able
to see an improvement even though nearly
all the fiber was removed because it was
just juice
shows there does seem to be something
special in the plant but can you get the
benefit just eating the stuff
let's find out
the effects of black and red cabbage on
oxidized ldl
and by black cabbage they mean lacinato
kale also known as dinosaur tuscan kale
they had people eat a bag of frozen kale
and cabbage a day for just two weeks
which is you know it's great because you
know you just keep it in the freezer
pre-wash pre-chop just throw into any
meal you're making
and
got significant reductions of total
cholesterol ldl cholesterol and even
blood sugar levels and the antioxidant
capacity of their blood went up and so
no surprise they demonstrated
significant decrease in oxidized ldl2
would it have been better to take that
red cabbage and ferment it into
sauerkraut
red or purple cabbage one of my favorite
vegetables packed with antioxidants yet
dirt cheap and seems to last forever in
the fridge and it's pretty juicy and
tasty i try to slice shreds off in any
meal i'm making but when you ferment it
not only do you add way too much salt
but you end up wiping out some of the
nutrition
here's the big spike in antioxidant
capacity of your bloodstream in the
hours after eating fresh red cabbage
cut down
by almost 30 percent if you ate the same
amount in fermented form
does cabbage have to be raw though no
some cooking techniques may improve the
antioxidant activity in kale and red
cabbage the effects of the cooking
process can be positive since cooking
softens the vegetable tissues helping
your body extract the active compounds
however cooking can also be negative
because heat treatment can degrade some
of the compounds they looked at a
variety of different cooking methods and
concluded steaming may be considered the
best home cooking technique to prepare
kale and red cabbage
but with foods that healthy the truly
best way to prepare them is whatever way
will get you to eat the most of them
[Music]
i